lpu.in 2009-11-27

# Welcome to Lovely Professional University

The basic purpose of the Privacy Policy statement is to enable you to understand that as a customer we value privacy of the information provided or obtained through the visits or usage of our website. This policy clearly states the manner in which the information is collected or used. You are advised to read the Privacy policy carefully. By accessing the services provided, you agree to the collection and use of information in the manner provided in the Privacy Policy.

**What information do we collect?**

The information is generally collected whenever you visit our web-site which does not disclose your personal identity like:

  1. IP address, assigned to the computer which you use
  2. The domain server through which you assess our site
  3. The type of web browser you are using
  4. Date and time of your access to our site

There will be certain cases, while using the site, you will be required to provide your information like:

  1. name including first, middle and last name
  2. contact address and/or mobile number
  3. ZIP/PIN Codes
  4. E-mail address or alternate e-mail address
  5. Other information as may be required as per registration process

However certain information may also be collected as under:

  1. about the pages you visit/access
  2. the number of times you access the page
  3. the links you click on our site

**How is the information used?**

We use the personal information to:

  1. Take, process or execute your requests, process or obtain payment or notify you of the status of your requests
  2. Provide you latest announcements.
  3. Preserve social history as governed by existing laws or policies.
  4. Contact you as a survey respondent
  5. Notify you, if you win any contest

**Disclosure of the information**

**Internal:**

We use the information we collect about you in order to provide our services and process your transaction and to provide you best service. We give access to individually identifiable information about our users only to those employees who require it to fulfill customer service requests

We will not use your financial information for any other purpose other than to complete a transaction with you.

**External:**

We do not rent, sell or share your personal information and will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information to third parties unless:

  1. We have your permission
  2. Required to complete your transaction 
  3. To help investigate, prevent or take action regarding unlawful and illegal activities, suspected fraud, potential threat to the safety or security of any person, violations of terms of use or to defend against legal claims 
  4. Special circumstances such as compliance with subpoenas, court orders, requests/order, notices from legal authorities or law enforcement agencies requiring such disclosure 

**Opting out the services**

Upon request, we will block/ remove your personally identifiable information from our database. However, the information will remain stored in archive on our servers.

**Security**

We take appropriate steps to protect the information you share with us. We have implemented such technology and security features and strict policy guidelines to safeguard the privacy of your personally identifiable information from unauthorized access and improper use or disclosure.

However, it is our constant endeavor to safeguard all your personal information, but the process of flow of information through usage of internet can't be made 100% secure. By using this site, you agree that we will have no liability for disclosure of your personal information due to errors in transmission or unauthorized acts of third parties.

**Revisions Modifications/Amendments to the Privacy Policy.**

This privacy policy may be revised/ modified/ amended at any point of time and the revised/ modified/ amended policy will be placed on the site. Such revision/ modification/ amendment will be effective from the date as may be decided.
